YINWEI ZHANG

Z zhangyinwei1994@gmail.com · **८** (+1) 520-486-7382 · **in** YINWEI · **%** https://yinwei-zhang.github.io/

SUMMARY

Ph.D. candidate with 1.5 years of industrial experience in machine learning and 5 years Ph.D. research experience in statistical modeling with a variety of programming languages. Passionate in implementing/developing machine learning pipeline. Mission-oriented real-world problem solver.

EDUCATION

University of Arizona, United States

<i>Ph.D.</i> Candidate in Systems and Industrial Engineering	2018-Present
M.Sc. in Statistics&Data Science	2020-Present
M.Sc. in Engineering Management	2016-2018

Jingchu University of Technology, China

B.S. in Process Equipment and Control Engineering

2012 - 2016

C TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- Soft skills: communication, writing, leadership
- Platforms: Windows, MacOS, Linux, Docker
- Programming skills: Python, R, Matlab, SAS, SQL
- Software & Libraries: TorchLua, TensorFlow/PyTorch, Sklearn, Numpy, Pandas Blender, ROS, CARLA, Autoware

EXPERIENCES

Research Intern, ABB, Raleigh, NC

Jan, 2020 - Aug, 2021

- Selected applicable neural networks for robots in **industrial applications** and **manufacturing processes** by literature review
- Collaborated with international groups to collect the data, and proposed a novel efficient data collection mechanism
- Trained and tested the networks **parallelly** for **regression** and/or **classification** tasks in a Linux based multi-GPU server based on **Tensorflow** and **PvTorch**
- Developed the pipeline for serving the trained neural networks by using **TensorFlow Serving** in **Docker**
- Improved the robustness of the neural network by designing a novel data augmentation algorithm in Python
- Evaluated the sensitivity of the NN to the image features by developing a mask-based method, improving the **interpretability** of the NN
- Created the synthetic industrial environments in **blender** to evaluate the performances of the NN under various conditions
- Cooperated with project managers to generate **intellectual properties** and write scientific reports

President, INFORMS Student Chapter, University of Arizona

Sep, 2021 - Present

- Lead the chapter members to collaborate with the department for organizing social events
- Analyze students' demands and initiate a new series of workshop that is helpful to students

Teaching Assistant, Quality Engineering, University of Arizona

Jan, 2021 - May, 2021

- Supported learning unsupervised anomaly detection based on statistical modeling
- Demonstrated supervised model selection/training for efficient anomaly detection with historical well-labeled data
- Illustrated model evaluation based on confusion matrix, i.e., true positive, true negative, false positive, and false negative

Teaching Assistant, Fundamentals of Data Science for Engineers, University of Arizona Aug, 2021 - Dec, 2021

- Supported learning principles of data pre-processing, e.g., data correcting, data completing, data creating, and data converting
- Assisted in understanding algorithms for supervise/unsupervise learning
- Displayed evaluation mechanisms, e.g., Precision, Recall, and F1-score
- Demonstrated Python and libraries, e.g., Sklearn, Numpy, and Pandas

Reliability Quantification of the Autonomous Vehicle, Tucson, AZ

- 2022
- Developed a physics-based simulation pipeline in **Docker** for quantifying the safety of the autonomous vehicle
- Designed **Python**-based modules for multi-sourced data fusion collected from different sensors, significantly improved the robustness of the decision-making of the autonomous vehicle
- Incorporated deep learning algorithm into the pipeline and studied its performance by injecting real-world based sensor errors
- Predicted the possible false positives and false negatives by proposing a statistical model based on the collected data

Anomaly Detection via Statistical Learning, Tucson, AZ

2019

- Developed a **statistical machine learning** model based on the additive regularized regression model for **anomaly detection/classification** in high dimensional spatio-temporal data in **MATLAB**
- Regularized the model coefficients with different norms, i.e., L_1 and L_2 regularization, according to their physical meaning
- Estimated the model parameters by **dimension reduction** and a gradient-based **optimization** algorithm
- The results show that it can reduce false-alarm rate from over 70% to sub 1%, and ensure detection rate at over 99%

Coursework Project on Product Assessment, Tucson, AZ

2018

- Collected one batch of products and measured the weight for each product
- Estimated the sample mean and sample variance of the weight
- Built hypothesis to test the equality between the mean weight and the designated weight by T-test
- The **p-value** showed that the weight for this batch is significant

PRESENTATION

- Xia, S., **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J. (2020). Investigation of Curing Process Heterogeneity from Raman Spectrum via CP Decomposition. *INFORMS Annual Meeting*.
- **Zhang, Y.** (2019). Tutorial: Applications of Spatial-Temporal Data Analytics in Industry. *Grand Lab Slam Workshop*, University of Arizona, Tucson.
- **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J., Lansey, K. (2019). Functional Data Analytics for Detecting Bursts in Water Distribution Systems. *IN-FORMS Annual Meeting*, Seattle.
- **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J., Son, Y. (2018). Effective and Efficient Moving Object Detection by a Moving Camera, *INFORMS Annual Meeting*, Phoenix.

PUBLICATION

- Pan, F., **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J., Head, L., Elli, M., & Alvarez, I. (2022). Quantifying error propagation in multi-stage perception system of autonomous vehicles via physics-based Simulation. *Winter Simulation Conference*, Singapore.
- Zhang, Y., Zhang, T., Liu, J., Kang, W., Liang, R., & Potter, B. (2022). Profile extraction for optical lens curing process with Image-based Regularized Tensor Decomposition. *Proceedings of the 2022 International Symposium on Flexible Automation*, Japan.
- Zhang, T., **Zhang**, Y., & Liu, J., Smooth-sparse decomposition in the image based on alternative smooth direction Model, (on-going).
- Nikravesh, Y., **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J., & Frantziskonis, G.N (2022). A partition and microstructure-based method for large-scale topology optimization. *Mechanics of Materials*, Volume 166.
- Peterson, R. L., Shea, K. D., Liu, J., Luque, K., Powell, J., **Zhang, Y**., Williams, D. K., Martin-Plank, L., Heasley, B. J., Phillips, L. R., & Crist, J. D. (2021). Family caregiving context: a pilot study. *The Arizona Nurse*, April.
- **Zhang, Y.**, Lansey, K., & Liu, J. (2020). Detecting bursts in water distribution system via penalized functional decomposition. IEEM Conference (honorable mention award).
- Lee, S., Jain, S., **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J., & Son, Y. (2020). A multi-paradigm simulation for the implementation of digital twins in surveillance application. IISE Conference.
- Lee, S., Jain, S., Yuan, Y., **Zhang, Y.**, Yang, H., Liu, J., & Son, Y. (2019). Design and development of a DDDAMS-based border surveillance system via UVs and hybrid simulations. *Expert Systems With Applications*, 109-123.

PATENT

System and method to generate augmented training data for neural network, No. PCT/US21/37798

- Robotic systems and methods used with installation of component parts
- Robotic systems and methods used to update training of a neural network based upon neural networks outputs